<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>20mph on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</title>
    <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/categories/20mph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 20mph on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/categories/20mph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20&#39;s plenty - let the BBC know</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/11/04/20-s-plenty-let-the-bbc-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/11/04/20-s-plenty-let-the-bbc-know/</guid>
      <description>BBC Morning Live is looking for opinions about 20mph speed limits &amp;ndash; this is the perfect time to get people talking about this important issue&amp;hellip;
You can tweet @BBCMorningLive or use the following button to send an e-mail &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve added some text prompts to make this easier&amp;hellip; but obviously you should write whatever you think!
Help me send an email to BBC Morning Live
(or if the button gives you trouble, try this link)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rectory Road Zebra crossing build-out</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/06/07/rectory-road-zebra-crossing-build-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/06/07/rectory-road-zebra-crossing-build-out/</guid>
      <description>Good news! A zebra crossing on Rectory Road that has been the site of many near-misses, some involving school-age children, is slated to get a major upgrade. According to a message from Cllr Penny Gowland, Via East Midlands has agreed to &amp;ldquo;build out&amp;rdquo; the zebra crossing. This will make pedestrians more visble to road users and encourage drivers and cyclists to slow down. (Via East Midlands is the county-council owned civil engineering company that deals with road improvements for the council).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding 3x more deadly than previously thought</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/05/15/speeding-3x-more-deadly-than-previously-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/05/15/speeding-3x-more-deadly-than-previously-thought/</guid>
      <description>Wow! Even stats19 data paints picture that&amp;rsquo;s far too rosy An article in the Sunday Times describes how accident data from the scene of collisions drastically underestimates the effects of speeding.
&amp;ldquo;If the rest of the country follows the same patterns as London and Manchester then there would be an increase in speed being a contributory factor in road deaths by about three times.”, according to Detective Chief Superintendent Andy Cox (Lincolnshire police, national lead for fatal collision investigation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primary school community poster competition</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/03/31/primary-school-community-poster-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/03/31/primary-school-community-poster-competition/</guid>
      <description>In amazing effort, the students at the West Bridgford Junior School have put their creativity into designing posters to make people think about slowing down!
Mrs Arnold and the Community Hub Team at the school organised an art competition and got an amazing response across all year groups.
You can see all the art work at https://wbjs-art.netlify.app/
The four winning entries (after intense voting) were:
Look out for giant versions of them around the school!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unanimous council support for motion to explore 20mph in Nottinghamshire</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/29/unanimous-council-support-for-motion-to-explore-20mph-in-nottinghamshire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/29/unanimous-council-support-for-motion-to-explore-20mph-in-nottinghamshire/</guid>
      <description>Great news about efforts to make the roads in our neighbourhoods safer and more attractive for walking, running, cycling, and generally being active.
Nottinghamshire county council has voted unanimously in support of a motion to explore 20mph in residential areas across Nottinghamshire (see also coverage on the local news). While &amp;ldquo;exploring 20mph&amp;rdquo; may sound like hedging, I personally think that the buy-in and support on show from all sides (across party affiliations) is an important step in the right direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nottinghamshire County Council debates 20mph motion</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/19/nottingham-county-council-debates-20mph-motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/19/nottingham-county-council-debates-20mph-motion/</guid>
      <description>Happy new year, with the hope that 2022 may be less messed up than the previous 2 years. First and foremost with less COVID-19 and more good health for everyone.
  Interesting times ahead, as a motion on 20mph in residential areas is on the agenda at the full county council meeting on Thursday 20 Jan 2022.
At this stage, the discussion is not quite about adopting the 20mph limit wholesale, but whether to task the Transport &amp;amp; Environment Committee &amp;ldquo;with exploring the feasibility of implementing a 20MPH speed limit on residential roads&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20mph speed limits elsewhere - uptake &#43; positive outcomes</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/17/20mph-speed-limits-elsewhere-uptake-positive-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/17/20mph-speed-limits-elsewhere-uptake-positive-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>To see the old year out and a hopefully much better 2022 in, a quick reminder on two points:
  a recent decision in the Scottish Borders Council shows that 20mph can work and is popular!1
  to let your councillors know what you think (hopes as well as concerns&amp;hellip;)
  What about the Scottish Borders? Scottish Borders Council agree by 26-5 to keep the 20mph limits set throughout communities after very positive speed reduction outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz time. How long does it take to stop a car?</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</guid>
      <description>Two quick questions to make you think about your driving habits. It&amp;rsquo;s been many years for most of us since we had to answer them for a driving test&amp;hellip;
Stopping distances...  What&#39;s the typical stopping distance for a car travelling at 30mph? 6 car lengths, about 23m. Before most people can react and start hitting the breaks, the car has travelled about 10m
A car hitting a pedestrian at 27mph is equivalent to falling out out a 3rd story window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Transport and Environment Committee</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/26/letter-to-transport-and-environment-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/26/letter-to-transport-and-environment-committee/</guid>
      <description>many items on Notts CC agenda &amp;hellip; which means that the petition (and motion) to consider 20mph default speed limit couldn&amp;rsquo;t be discussed. Tweet from Cllr Penny Gowland:
Still didn&amp;#39;t get to discuss 20s plenty @schluppeck .. 4th time lucky
&amp;mdash; Penny Gowland (@Penny_Gowland) November 25, 2021  But things don&amp;rsquo;t happen instantly - and so I have decided to be constructive with the extra time and to write to the Transport &amp;amp; Environment Committee of the Nottinghamshire CC in the meantime.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
