<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nottingham on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</title>
    <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/tags/nottingham/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nottingham on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/tags/nottingham/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quiz time. How long does it take to stop a car?</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</guid>
      <description>Two quick questions to make you think about your driving habits. It&amp;rsquo;s been many years for most of us since we had to answer them for a driving test&amp;hellip;
Stopping distances...  What&#39;s the typical stopping distance for a car travelling at 30mph? 6 car lengths, about 23m. Before most people can react and start hitting the breaks, the car has travelled about 10m
A car hitting a pedestrian at 27mph is equivalent to falling out out a 3rd story window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let your councillor know that 20&#39;s plenty</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/10/let-your-councillor-know-that-20-s-plenty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/10/let-your-councillor-know-that-20-s-plenty/</guid>
      <description>Click on your ward on the map below to get a ready-made e-mail that you can send to your local councillor to show support for 20mph across West Bridgford.
Update (2021-11-11, 6pm): (County) Cllr Penny Gowland is now cc&amp;rsquo;ed on the messages automatically.
When you click on the map, your e-mail programme should pop up with some pre-prepared text and the correct e-mail addresses for the councillors in your ward. (Any problems, please let me know).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic traffic data from `stats19`</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/13/basic-traffic-data-from-stats19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/13/basic-traffic-data-from-stats19/</guid>
      <description>To raise awareness about the actual number of traffic accidents in our neighbourhood I have decided to do some number crunching and plotting (since this is what I do a lot of in my day job as a scientist).
I will try to bring out the numbers as clearly as I can (and I will let them speak for themselves). There is no claim for completeness, but if you want to inspect how I went about it the code (in R) is published on my github page: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make West Bridgford a 20mph zone</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/11/make-west-bridgford-a-20mph-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/11/make-west-bridgford-a-20mph-zone/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of 11 October I decided to write a public facebook post about making West Bridgford a 20mph zone. The aim would be to lower the speed limit on residential roads from 30mph to 20mph.
The arguments in favour are simple:
  safety there are many, many children on the road (pedestrians and cyclists) at all times of day and 20mph is much safer
  environment, both in terms of emissions and how people not in cars can make use of the roads</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
