<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>20mph on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</title>
    <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/tags/20mph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 20mph on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/tags/20mph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unanimous council support for motion to explore 20mph in Nottinghamshire</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/29/unanimous-council-support-for-motion-to-explore-20mph-in-nottinghamshire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/29/unanimous-council-support-for-motion-to-explore-20mph-in-nottinghamshire/</guid>
      <description>Great news about efforts to make the roads in our neighbourhoods safer and more attractive for walking, running, cycling, and generally being active.
Nottinghamshire county council has voted unanimously in support of a motion to explore 20mph in residential areas across Nottinghamshire (see also coverage on the local news). While &amp;ldquo;exploring 20mph&amp;rdquo; may sound like hedging, I personally think that the buy-in and support on show from all sides (across party affiliations) is an important step in the right direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nottinghamshire County Council debates 20mph motion</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/19/nottingham-county-council-debates-20mph-motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/01/19/nottingham-county-council-debates-20mph-motion/</guid>
      <description>Happy new year, with the hope that 2022 may be less messed up than the previous 2 years. First and foremost with less COVID-19 and more good health for everyone.
  Interesting times ahead, as a motion on 20mph in residential areas is on the agenda at the full county council meeting on Thursday 20 Jan 2022.
At this stage, the discussion is not quite about adopting the 20mph limit wholesale, but whether to task the Transport &amp;amp; Environment Committee &amp;ldquo;with exploring the feasibility of implementing a 20MPH speed limit on residential roads&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20mph speed limits elsewhere - uptake &#43; positive outcomes</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/17/20mph-speed-limits-elsewhere-uptake-positive-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/17/20mph-speed-limits-elsewhere-uptake-positive-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>To see the old year out and a hopefully much better 2022 in, a quick reminder on two points:
  a recent decision in the Scottish Borders Council shows that 20mph can work and is popular!1
  to let your councillors know what you think (hopes as well as concerns&amp;hellip;)
  What about the Scottish Borders? Scottish Borders Council agree by 26-5 to keep the 20mph limits set throughout communities after very positive speed reduction outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz time. How long does it take to stop a car?</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</guid>
      <description>Two quick questions to make you think about your driving habits. It&amp;rsquo;s been many years for most of us since we had to answer them for a driving test&amp;hellip;
Stopping distances...  What&#39;s the typical stopping distance for a car travelling at 30mph? 6 car lengths, about 23m. Before most people can react and start hitting the breaks, the car has travelled about 10m
A car hitting a pedestrian at 27mph is equivalent to falling out out a 3rd story window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let your councillor know that 20&#39;s plenty</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/10/let-your-councillor-know-that-20-s-plenty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/10/let-your-councillor-know-that-20-s-plenty/</guid>
      <description>Click on your ward on the map below to get a ready-made e-mail that you can send to your local councillor to show support for 20mph across West Bridgford.
Update (2021-11-11, 6pm): (County) Cllr Penny Gowland is now cc&amp;rsquo;ed on the messages automatically.
When you click on the map, your e-mail programme should pop up with some pre-prepared text and the correct e-mail addresses for the councillors in your ward. (Any problems, please let me know).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20mph has wide support across the UK, not just WB</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/07/20mph-has-wide-support-across-the-uk-not-just-wb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/07/20mph-has-wide-support-across-the-uk-not-just-wb/</guid>
      <description>More than 70% of people in Britain support 20mph speed limits.1 There are many benefits, but three big ones are that it is
 healthier&amp;hellip; by encouraging people to hop on the bike or walk on more friendly roads safer&amp;hellip; larger speeds = more accidents and more serious injury cleaner&amp;hellip; there is much less pollution at slower speeds, particularly for stop-and-go accelerating as is common in residential areas  People in NG support it There are plenty of places across the UK that are campaigning for 20mph and many, like Nottingham City2, have decided to go for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When do most pedestrians/cyclists get hit?</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/28/when-do-accidents-happen-updated-data-from-dft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/28/when-do-accidents-happen-updated-data-from-dft/</guid>
      <description>Since I first put up a map of traffic accidents / casualties at the start of October ’21, the Department for Transport has updated its openly accessible data. This means that now data for the years between 2016 and 2020 is easily accessible.
I think knowing when accidents are most common is as important as known where they occur across our county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of informal survey</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/15/results-of-informal-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/15/results-of-informal-survey/</guid>
      <description>Together with my original facebook post, I put together a very short survey and asked the following questions:
“What do you think about making the speed limit on all residential roads in WB 20mph?”
 “Any other ideas / comments / questions?”
 “Your e-mail address (optional)” - for letting people know what I found out.
  An important caveat here is that this is not a scientific poll and just because there are lots of positive views expressed here doesn’t necessarily mean that the same proportion of people in all of WB feel this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic traffic data from `stats19`</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/13/basic-traffic-data-from-stats19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/13/basic-traffic-data-from-stats19/</guid>
      <description>To raise awareness about the actual number of traffic accidents in our neighbourhood I have decided to do some number crunching and plotting (since this is what I do a lot of in my day job as a scientist).
I will try to bring out the numbers as clearly as I can (and I will let them speak for themselves). There is no claim for completeness, but if you want to inspect how I went about it the code (in R) is published on my github page: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make West Bridgford a 20mph zone</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/11/make-west-bridgford-a-20mph-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/11/make-west-bridgford-a-20mph-zone/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of 11 October I decided to write a public facebook post about making West Bridgford a 20mph zone. The aim would be to lower the speed limit on residential roads from 30mph to 20mph.
The arguments in favour are simple:
  safety there are many, many children on the road (pedestrians and cyclists) at all times of day and 20mph is much safer
  environment, both in terms of emissions and how people not in cars can make use of the roads</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
