<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>facebook on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</title>
    <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in facebook on Make West Bridgford a 20 mph zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rectory Road Zebra crossing build-out</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/06/07/rectory-road-zebra-crossing-build-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2022/06/07/rectory-road-zebra-crossing-build-out/</guid>
      <description>Good news! A zebra crossing on Rectory Road that has been the site of many near-misses, some involving school-age children, is slated to get a major upgrade. According to a message from Cllr Penny Gowland, Via East Midlands has agreed to &amp;ldquo;build out&amp;rdquo; the zebra crossing. This will make pedestrians more visble to road users and encourage drivers and cyclists to slow down. (Via East Midlands is the county-council owned civil engineering company that deals with road improvements for the council).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiz time. How long does it take to stop a car?</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/12/07/quiz-time-how-long-does-it-take-to-stop-a-car/</guid>
      <description>Two quick questions to make you think about your driving habits. It&amp;rsquo;s been many years for most of us since we had to answer them for a driving test&amp;hellip;
Stopping distances...  What&#39;s the typical stopping distance for a car travelling at 30mph? 6 car lengths, about 23m. Before most people can react and start hitting the breaks, the car has travelled about 10m
A car hitting a pedestrian at 27mph is equivalent to falling out out a 3rd story window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20mph has wide support across the UK, not just WB</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/07/20mph-has-wide-support-across-the-uk-not-just-wb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/11/07/20mph-has-wide-support-across-the-uk-not-just-wb/</guid>
      <description>More than 70% of people in Britain support 20mph speed limits.1 There are many benefits, but three big ones are that it is
 healthier&amp;hellip; by encouraging people to hop on the bike or walk on more friendly roads safer&amp;hellip; larger speeds = more accidents and more serious injury cleaner&amp;hellip; there is much less pollution at slower speeds, particularly for stop-and-go accelerating as is common in residential areas  People in NG support it There are plenty of places across the UK that are campaigning for 20mph and many, like Nottingham City2, have decided to go for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make West Bridgford a 20mph zone</title>
      <link>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/11/make-west-bridgford-a-20mph-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schluppeck.github.io/make-wb-20mph/2021/10/11/make-west-bridgford-a-20mph-zone/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of 11 October I decided to write a public facebook post about making West Bridgford a 20mph zone. The aim would be to lower the speed limit on residential roads from 30mph to 20mph.
The arguments in favour are simple:
  safety there are many, many children on the road (pedestrians and cyclists) at all times of day and 20mph is much safer
  environment, both in terms of emissions and how people not in cars can make use of the roads</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
